http://web.cse.ohio-state.edu/~deng.595

CONTACT Information Department of Computer Science and Engineering The Ohio State University Email: deng.595@osu.edu GitHub: xiang-deng

# RESEARCH INTERESTS

My research interests lie in NLP and data mining, with emphasis on knowledge discovery and utilization from heterogeneous sources. The aim is to build AI-powered data systems that can assist with information acquisition and decision making for regular users as well as domain experts in Digital Era. Specifically, my recent research focuses on the following directions: (1) Large-scale pretraining and representation learning for data from heterogeneous sources, such as plain text, web documents, knowledge graphs, and databases; both for general and domain-specific applications. (2) Building natural language interfaces (e.g., question answering, semantic parsing, and dialog systems) with varied data and services as backend.

EDUCATION

## The Ohio State University, Columbus, OH

2018 - 2023 (expected)

Studying towards Ph.D., Computer Science and Engineering

- Advisor: Prof. Huan Sun
- Major: Artificial Intelligence; Minor: Database, Graphics

## University of Science and Technology of China, Hefei, China

B.Eng. Computer Science, School of The Gifted Young

• The Talent Program in Computer and Information Science

Professional Experience

#### The Ohio State University

Aug 2018 - present

2014 - 2018

Graduate Research Associate Supervisor: Prof. Huan Sun

- Prompting and reasoning with Large Language Models for solving complex tasks.
- Building dialog system that can assist users in accomplishing tasks. (OSU Tacobot team, ranked  $3^{rd}$  place in the inaugural Alexa Prize TaskBot Challenge.)
- Textual and tabular data understanding via pre-training. (VLDB'21, EMNLP'21, SIGMOD Research Highlight'22. Collaboration with Google Research under Google Faculty Research Award.)
- Relation Extraction with extra signals from Web Tables. (EMNLP'19)
- Question answering and tabular query resolution with Knowledge Base.

Google

May 2022 - Aug 2022

Research Intern, Google Research NYC

Supervisor: Vasilisa Bashlovkina\*, Feng Han, Simon Baumgartner

• Financial market sentiment anlysis on social media content.

Amazon

May 2021 - Aug 2021

Applied Scientist Intern, Product Graph

Supervisor: Prashant Shiralkar\*, Colin Lockard, Binxuan Huang

• Robust and generalizable representation learning for semi-structured web pages. The resulting model brings significant improvement under zero-shot and few-shot settings, which greatly reduces human annotation efforts.

#### Microsoft Research

May 2020 - Aug 2020

Research Intern, Natural Language Processing Group

Supervisor: Matthew Richardson\*, Ahmed Awadallah, Christopher Meek, Oleksandr Polozov

• Natural Language to SQL, with a focus on generalization ability in real-world applications. By weakly supervised pretraining using existing text-table parallel data on the web, we enhance the model's performance on value prediction and column selection, especially when the access to actual database content is limited at runtime. (NAACL'21)

### Microsoft Research Asia

 $\rm Dec~2017$  - May 2018

Research Intern, Natural Language Computing Group

Supervisor: Lei Cui

• News Recommendation and Summarization.

### The Ohio State University

July 2017 - Nov 2017

Visiting Student

Supervisor: Prof. Huan Sun

• Question Answering over Knowledge Base with Web Information.

# University of Science and Technology of China Undergraduate Research

Feb 2017 - June 2017

Dr. Qi Liu

• Representation Learning for Complex Network.

#### **PUBLICATIONS**

Bootstrapping a User-Centered Task-Oriented Dialogue System

Shijie Chen, Ziru Chen, **Xiang Deng**, Ashley Lewis, Lingbo Mo, Samuel Stevens, Zhen Wang, Xiang Yue, Tianshu Zhang, Yu Su, Huan Sun

Alexa Prize Proceedings, 2022

 $3^{rd}$  place in the Alexa Prize TaskBot Challenge

Shepherd Pre-trained Language Models to Develop a Train of Thought: An Iterative Prompting Approach

Boshi Wang, **Xiang Deng**, Huan Sun

arXiv preprint, 2022

DOM-LM: Learning Generalizable Representations for HTML Documents

Xiang Deng, Prashant Shiralkar, Colin Lockard, Binxuan Huang, Huan Sun arXiv preprint, 2022

ReasonBERT: Pre-trained to Reason with Distant Supervision

Xiang Deng, Yu Su, Alyssa Lees, You Wu, Cong Yu, and Huan Sun

Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, (EMNLP), 2021

Structure-Grounded Pretraining for Text-to-SQL

**Xiang Deng**, Ahmed Hassan Awadallah, Christopher Meek, Oleksandr Polozov, Huan Sun, and Matthew Richardson

Annual Conference of the North American Chapter of the Association for Computational Linguistics, (NAACL), 2021

TURL: Table Understanding through Representation Learning

Xiang Deng, Huan Sun, Alyssa Lees, You Wu, and Cong Yu

International Conference on Very Large Data Bases, (VLDB), 2021

SIGMOD Research Highlight, 2022

Leveraging 2-hop Distant Supervision from Table Entity Pairs for Relation Extraction Xiang Deng, Huan Sun

Conference on Empirical Methods in Natural Language Processing, (EMNLP), 2019

Easy-to-Hard: Leveraging Simple Questions for Complex Question Generation

Jie Zhao, Xiang Deng, Huan Sun

arXiv preprint, 2019

Automatic Table completion using Knowledge Base

Bortik Bandyopadhyay, Xiang Deng, Goonmeet Bajaj, Huan Sun, and Srinivasan

Parthasarathy arXiv preprint, 2019

AWARDS 3rd place in the Alexa Prize TaskBot Challenge, Amazon 2022

SIGMOD Research Highlight, SIGMODStudent Travel Award, KDDStudent Scholarship, USTC 2015, 2016, 2017 Freshman Scholarship, USTC

PROFESSIONAL Program Committee/Reviewer:

SERVICE ACL ARR, SUKI 2022, NLP4Prog 2021; NLPCC 2020, 2021, 2022

Secondary/External Reviewer: KDD 2020; NAACL 2019; KDD 2019

TEACHING Syllabus of Digital Logic Lab, USTC Fall, 2016

EXPERIENCE Teaching Assistant

Programming Python, PyTorch, Tensorflow, Spark, C++, Java, SQL

Languages and Frameworks